KIRK VICKERS: In the fitness world and the rehab world, these physioballs have become real popular.
Some people call them Swiss balls.
But these balls are--it can be a great training tool especially when we talk about core strengthening and core stability.
I'm going to demonstrate a movement--a fairly simple movement that you can do on this to create more stability and control through the body and through the hips and the pelvis, through that core region.
I want to set the ball down.
A quick note, when we sit on the ball or when we're doing any seated motions on a physioball, we want to make sure that our knees are in line with our hips.
We don't want our knees too high but we don't want to let knees too low.
As we put our feet straight out from under us and we've got this nice 90-degree angle, we should have a ball that stabilizes our hips.
It should come off straight off with the ball.
The movement that we're going to do here is we're going to activate the hip flexor and create a lot of core stability.
We're just going to raise the leg and hold it for a 30-second count.
If we want to make this more challenging, we can put our arms over our head and do the same thing.
Switch legs, hold it for a 30-second count.
For those of you that are just starting this, it might be nice to have a wall close to you or put your ball close into a corner, making sure that the ball doesn't touch the corner so you still have that stability and that movement through the ball.